JOHNBOSCO IKECHUKWU OPARAH

[FRONTEND ENGINEER]

+2348034569390 | boscomary67@gmail.com | Lagos, Nigeria.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Frontend software engineer with 2+ years of experience designing, developing managing complex e-commerce site and internal frameworks. Highly skilled in working with web technologies and working knowledge of code versioning. Well-versed in working in Scrum and Agile environments. An enthusiastic team player and deep creative thinker.

TECH STACK

Front End	JavaScript, React Js, Context API, React-hooks, CSS3, Tailwind CSS, SASS, Material UI, Flowbite, Webpack, Testing(Jest, React testing Library), Redux, Next Js
Back End	JavaScript, Node.Js, Express, APIs
Data Stores	MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB,
Web Servers	Apache HTTP Server, Nginx
Operating Systems	Mac OS, Windows 10, window 11

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer| Freelance | Lagos, Nigeria.

2020 - Present

- Created and launched an ecommerce website that allowed prospective customer to shop, order and pay through the site payment platform.
- Developed a responsive portfolio with sanity.io.
- Adhered to SEO best practices while designing sites and public-facing online deliverables ensuring page accessibility by 40%.
- Technologies: [React, Sass, Flowbite-tailwind, JavaScript, Sanity.io]

Automobile Computer Tech. | JustCode | Lagos, Nigeria. 2018 – 2020

JustCode is an elite Automobile programming hub and training school that equips high-potential individuals with world-class automobile coding skills. Experience practical learning through real-life projects and internship placements over a six-month period.

- Performs diagnostic routines, report findings and gives recommendations in order to improve system reliability and durability.
- Read and write chip code on ECU memory transponder. Performed Onboard, OBD2, EEPROM Programming.
- Calibrate and optimize OBD engine and aftertreatment functions meeting Customer and Regulatory Requirements.
- <u>Technologies</u>: [Orange 5 Programming machine, OBD2 Diagnosis Device]

OTHER EXPERIENCES

Learning Facilitator | Christ the King Computer Institute | Nigeria

2007 - 2009

EDUCATION

Madonna University | Enugu, Nigeria

• BEng Mechanical Engineering (Honours)

CERTIFICATIONS

Scrum Fundamentals Certified Alison	2023
Agile Essentials Certified Alison	2023

PROFILES

Linkedln: https://www.linkedin.com/in/johnbosco-oparah/

Twitter: https://twitter.com/OparahJohnbosco Github/StackOverflow/... //github.com/lykecode93